# 哈喽大家好
Hello everyone
# 最近很多粉丝说这个火锅鸡的调料
Many fans have asked about the seasoning of hotpot chicken
# 就是不会做
They don't know how to use it
# 然后正好我今天就开一份来做
So today, I will open a pack and cook with it
# 我家这个鸡这个鸡是我伯爷养的
This chicken is raised by my uncle
# 这个鸡没有多大
It’s not so big though
# 去年冬至就买起喂了几个月才这么大点
It's still so small, although we bought and raised it since the last winter solstice
# 它光吃不长今天我就杀来吃了
It eats a lot but never grows so I cook it today
# 这一包是底料
This bag is seasoning base
# 里面有牛油
There’s beef tallow inside
# 有一些辣椒一起炒的
Cooked with chilis
# 然后这一包的话是泡椒
This is a bag of pickled chili
# 里面有姜有泡椒这个泡椒不是很辣
There is ginger and pickled chili inside, it’s not very spicy
# 先把这个倒出来
Pour out this first
# 喂了几大个月才两三斤
It’s only two or three jin (1 or 1.5kg) even it’s several months old
# 不肯长
It refused to grow
# 那它吃些什么
What does it usually eat
# 还喂得好诶 拿糠饭喂它
We feed it with leftovers and bran
# 太肥了也要被吃
It will be cooked too if it grew so fat
# 太瘦了也不得行
Same situation if it’s too skinny
# 管它瘦不瘦哦 我啃骨头嘛
I don't care if it’s skinny or not. I can gnaw the bones
# 好 我们这个的话
Alright let’s do it
# 如果吃的味道重一点把它切开
Cut it open if you like a stronger taste
# 吃的味道不重的话就直接放进去可以了
If you don’t, just put it in
# 然后这里面的这个水不要
We don’t need the water inside
# 这个切开都有盐味噶
It's still salty even if chopped?
# 嗯 切开了就更香
Yes, it’s more aromatic when chopped
# 这个刀拿给漆二娃整得好钝哦
Qi Erwa made this knife so blunt
# 她这一直磨都没磨一下
She didn’t even sharpen it for a bit
# 她随便什么都用现成
She likes using the ready-made stuff
# 好 把它宰了
Ok, let’s butcher it
# 喊漆二娃来嘛起码这个鸡要宰半个小时
It takes at least half an hour if Qi Erwa butchered it
# 为啥子啊
Why is that
# 她手脚慢
Because she is slow
# 是她嘛半边都没宰完
She won’t finish half in this time
# 不至于吧
Couldn’t be like this
# 害怕不至于
Could be, I'm afraid
# 她手脚慢又害怕搞到手
She acts slow and is afraid of being hurt
# 好 拿起去喂狗儿
Alright, just feed it to the dog
# 给个头给你吃听话点啊
Here's a head for you. Be a good boy!
# 你先吃完一个再吃嘛
You should eat another one after you finish one first
# 那么贪心
Oh don’t be so greedy
# 慢慢吃
Eat slowly
# 我们用这个笋子来烧
We cook it with this bamboo shoot
# 这个笋子要从中间切一下
We cut it in the middle
# 让它把里面的水流出来
Let the water inside flow out
# 对半切开就是
Just cut it evenly
# 好
OK
# 可以了 可以准备做了
Alright, let’s do it
# 这个焯不焯下水啊
Do we need to blanch it
# 要
Sure
# 好 现在我们就转小火烧半个小时
Ok we turn it to low heat for half an hour
# 然后待会儿提前5分钟把这个放下去
Then put it in 5 mins before finish
# 烧熟就可以吃了
We can eat it when well-braised
# 不用调味只放水就可以了
No need for extra seasoning, just water is enough
# 好啦 现在我们把这个放进去烧一会儿
Ok now we put it in and braise for a while
# 烧5分钟
About 5 minutes
# 好啦现在准备出锅了
Good, now it’s ready
# 尝一下我的火锅鸡
Try this hotpot chicken I made
# 诶呀 火锅鸡啊
Aya, hotpot chicken
# 泡椒味道的
With pickled chili flavor
# 这就是泡椒火锅鸡啊
This is actually pickled chili hotpot chicken
# 我没有加那个干辣椒
I didn’t add the dried chili pepper into it
# 烧的笋子噶
Is it braised with bamboo shoot?
# 嗯
Yeah
# 我还以为你先切得是苦瓜
I thought you prepared bitter gourd first
# 我整点来尝一下看耙没耙哦
Let me take some and see whether it’s tender or not
# 肉都耙了
The meat is so tender
# 好脆哦
And very crunchy
# 嗯 安逸
Hmm very nice
# 味道怎么样
How’s the taste?
# 可以可以
Good, good
# 你看那个狗儿都开始守嘴了
See? The dog is licking its mouth now
# 你不要慌 我们吃了来多
Be patient, wait after we finish
# 吃了的骨头拿给它嘛
We can give it the bones
# 我吃那种肉点的
I’ll eat the one with more meat
# 拿去这坨
Take this one
# 有了有了有了
Yeah got it got it
# 嗯还烧耙了的
It’s a tender one
# 安逸
Nice
# 我们这个火锅鸡就是说
Speaking of this hotpot chicken
# 你自己想弄什么鸡都可以
Any breed of chicken is ok
# 也可以放鸭子下去
Ducks are fine
# 还可以放鹅下去
Geese are good too
# 烧都没有问题
We can braise them well
# 也可以放兔子啊之类的
Same with rabbit meat
# 我下次给你多带几包下来
I’ll bring you more bags of seasoning next time
# 你想吃的时候随时开起
Whenever you want, just open it
# 给它煮就是
And just cook with it
# 但是你要记住不能放盐哦
But remember, don’t add salt
# 不放盐啊 你那个佐料里面就有盐的
No salt? The seasoning already contains salt
# 佐料里面盐那些都是调归一了的
All the seasonings are already well prepared in it.
# 辣椒那些都是调好了的
Including spiciness
# 什么都不放只加水
We only need to add water
# 现在整饮食吃跟漆二娃做的
Now cooking can be as lazy as...
# 懒人排骨一样只有那么懒了
as the "Lazy Man's Pork Ribs" made my Qi Erwa
# 整现成的
Using ready-made only
# 佐料啥样都不要
No seasoning at all
# 放到里面样样佐料都有了
Just put it in and get everything
# 伯娘吃鸡肉撒 你咬得动
Aunt, have some chicken? It's tender enough for you
# 嗯 我吃了的
Yes, I already had it
# 现在的人好安逸嘛
Nowadays, people are living such nice life
# 佐料什么的全部配归一又方便
All seasonings are ready-made and convenient
# 袋子一割开挤得锅里面
They just open the bag and pour it in the wok
# 一烧起就可以干了
cook it and then they can eat
# 我们农村还要现去准备
We still have to prepare everything in our village
# 整这样整那样
Like everything
# 关键是很多料你找不到
The point is, you can't get many of the ingredients
# 嗯
Hmm
# 好啦 本期视频就到这里
Alright, this episode is about it
# 买过这个的朋友们可以这样子试一下
Those who have bought it could try this way
# 就说你们之前不是有很多疑问吗
You guys had a lot of questions before
# 这个到底要不要加什么要不要加什么
Like should we add this seasoning or not
# 其实啥都不用加直接加水煮就可以了
Basically we don’t need to add anything except water
# 但是前提是要把鸡肉爆香
But we should bring out the aroma of the chicken at first
# 然后把泡椒的颜色爆出来
And bring out the color and flavor of the pickled chili
# 然后再把那个
And then cook that
# 火锅那个料放进去把它炒化
hotpot seasoning till it melts
# 再加水烧就行了
Then we just need to add water and heat up
# 什么都不用加
With nothing extra
# 记住了啊
Remember guys